They came. They saw. They changed their minds.
Wagons East! is a adventure, comedy, western film directed by Peter Markle.
After the 1860s Wild West, a group of misfit settlers - including ex-doctor Phil Taylor, prostitute Belle, and
homosexual bookseller Julian - decide they cannot live in their current situation in the west.
They hire a grizzled alcoholic wagon master by the name of James Harlow to
take them on a journey back to their hometowns in the East.
James Harlow, played by John Candy.
Phil Taylor, played by Richard Lewis.
Julian, played by John C. McGinley.
Belle, played by Ellen Greene.
Ben Wheeler, played by Robert Picardo.
John Slade, played by Ed Lauter.
Wagons East (sometimes styled as Wagons East!) is a 1994 American Western adventure comedy film directed by
Peter Markle, written by Matthew Carlson, and starring John Candy, Richard Lewis, John C.
McGinley, Ellen Greene, Robert Picardo, Rodney A.
Grant, and Ed Lauter.
It tells the story of an alcoholic wagon master who leads a group of
misfit settlers in the Wild West back to the East.
The film was released in the United States on August 26, 1994.
Filming took place in Sierra de Órganos National Park in the town
of Sombrerete, Mexico, and in Durango, Mexico.
During the final days of the film's production in Durango, Mexico,
John Candy died of a heart attack at the age of 43.
Script re-writes, a stand-in and special effects were used to complete his
remaining scenes, and it was released five months after his death.
The film marked Candy's penultimate performance, with the film being dedicated in memory of him as well as
the film being the last Carolco Pictures production to be distributed by TriStar Pictures.
The film was panned by critics, with a rare 0% rating on Rotten Tomatoes.
The film grossed $4.4 million at the box office.
The film explores themes of gunslinger, indian
territory, satire, native american, shootout.
The tone is lighthearted.